Sally B. Eddy

Sally graduated from the University of Portland (1966) with a degree in chemistry and minor in mathematics. She retired from PGP Valuation, Inc. in December 31, 2007, after 9.5 years in the appraisal field specializing in commercial real estate. Sally formed Commercial Appraisal & Consulting Services LLC, a real estate appraisal and consulting firm, in January 2008.



Sally concentrates in small cities, the Columbia River Gorge, and coastal communities in Oregon and Washington. She specializes in land, retail/office, industrial, schools, churches, marinas, residential subdivisions & condominiums, motels, and bed & breakfast inns.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelors of Science in Chemistry, Minor in Mathematics, Statistics and Economics, University of Portland

APPRAISAL INSTITUTE COURSES

Appraisal Principles

Appraisal Procedures

Basic Income Capitalization

General Applications

Standards of Professional Practice – A and B

Appraisal of Non-Conforming Uses

Real Estate Fraud: The Appraiser's Responsibilities & Liabilities

Elderly Care Facility Appraisal

Building Construction Technology: Methods and Materials

CONTINUING EDUCATION

The Uncertainties of Measure 37

Highest & Best Use

The Cost Approach

Sales Comparison Approach

FORMER ACTIVITIES

Between the early 1970s and Mid 1990s community based activities and those under private ownership included:

City of Washougal, WA Planning Commission

City of Washougal, WA City Council

Clark County Regional Planning Council (Regional Council of Governments)

Southwest Washington Hospital Foundations Board

Southwest Washington Independent Forward Thrust (SWIFT)

Southwest Washington Private Industry Council (Chaired a four-county consortium providing oversight for the Federal Jobs Training & Partnership Act in SW Washington) The Road Less Traveled: Special Purpose Properties

Valuation of Conservation Easements

2011 7-Hr USPAP

Business Ethics 2009

What Commercial Clients Would Like Appraisers to

Know

Introduction to Green Buildings: Principles &

Concepts

Small Hotel/Motel Valuation

IRS Valuation Summit 2011

Clark County Industrial Revenue Bond Public Corporation

Portland International Airport Noise Abatement Advisory Committee (Bi-State Appointment)

Loaned Executive to the American Red Cross

Owner, New Vista Development – Residential Speculative Development Company (Mid-1980s)

Owner Elan Construction – Specializing in the renovation of Single Family residences (Mid 1990s)

Project Manager for Habitat for Humanity – directed the construction of 5 single family residences for local families including an all woman's build.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Practicing Affiliate, Appraisal Institute 2015

National Association of Realtors 2014

Clatsop County Multiple Listing Service (Oregon) 2014

EXPERIENCE

Commercial Appraiser, PGP Valuation Inc., 9.5 Years, Retired (6/16/1998 – 12/31/2007)

Project Manager – Evergreen Habitat for Humanity, Vancouver, WA (1/1997 to 6/15/1998)

Self-Employed (9/1993 to 12/1996)

Prior Work History in the Pulp and Paper Industry, 27.5 years (Research Chemist, Product Development Manager, Shift Supervisor – Mill operations, Quality Control Supervisor)

STATE CERTIFICATIONS

Oregon, State Certified General Appraiser, License No. C000720

Washington, Certified General Real Estate Appraiser, License No. 1101733